Mohammad Akrami

Authorized to work in the US for any employer - Willing to relocate

Missoula, MT 59808 mfakrami85@gmail.com 406-207-3868

15 years of professional experience in Information Technology with five year in the USA and ten years abroad in different capacity. Over the past four years, I am managing WMMHC network infrastructure and data-center operations across Windows, Linux platforms.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

IT Systems Administrator

WMMHC

August 2018 to Present

- Direct administration of 50+ Windows 2008/2012 R2 Servers (Physical and Virtual), including rationalization.
- Windows Server and workstations monthly updates patching and testing.
- Hybrid Active Directory administration and maintenance.
- Deploy, configures, and maintains network infrastructure including Cisco routers and firewalls, Cisco Catalyst 2960/3560/SG300 managed POE switches, Patch panel installation and Aruba wireless access points.
- Manages the multi-site ERGO VOIP system, including installation and configuration of telecom equipment, extensions, and voicemail.
- Virtualize Windows servers via Hyper-V, consolidating hardware and increasing efficiency.
- Managing fully cloud-based Exchange Online/Office 365, Power BI dashboard customization, OneDrive management, Dynamics 365 Voice USL, and Microsoft Teams support
- Creating and Managing AD Group Policies for unifying user workstation experience based on IT policies.
- Maintaining Systems Center Configuration Manager (SCCM) for remote management of 450+ Window 10 workstations and laptops including Windows Endpoint Protection management and remote application deployment.
- Maintaining data retention, and disaster recovery plan using Microsoft Data Protection, Tera Stations NAS Manager including Physical offsite tape backups, and regular monthly data integrity testing.
- Network monitoring and alert management via PRTG. Leveraging PRTG's ability to run automated scripts and sensors on different hardware components for improving network efficiency and real-time monitoring.
- Imaging servers, workstations, and Laptops using Microsoft Deployment Tool Kit.
- Hybrid SharePoint server management and administration, including integration with Microsoft Power-BI for real-time data reporting and analysis.

VTC Specialist

WMMHC - Missoula, MT July 2018 to November 2018

- Provisioned MHC Polycom Video teleconferencing infrastructure consists of 3 physical Linux Servers, 4 virtual Linux servers, a conference bridge, and 80 Polycom endpoints.
- Administered, installed, and troubleshoot agency wide video conferencing infrastructure.
- Supported end-users by assisting with general VTC requests and provide support to external agencies on the usage of the MHC Polycom system.
- Provided application software support, Office 365 administration and management, Email Security Gateway monitoring, Polycom phone, and fax line installation.

IT Support Technician

WMMHC

August 2017 to November 2017

Oversaw the daily performance of computer systems including tape backups. Setup, tested and configured network, desktops, laptops and printers. Maintained company Track-IT database. Resolved technical issues for clients in person, on the phone and through e-mail. Coordinated hardware and software repair processes with vendors, Repaired, reinstalled software such as EHR/ AS400.

IT Coordinator

JRPC (Jeannette Rankin Peace Center) / Poverello Center October 2016 to July 2017

Maintained and administered computer networks and related computing environment including computer hardware, systems software, application software and configuration. Troubleshoot all peripherals computer-related office machines, including copiers, printers and postage machine. Upgraded network infrastructure for JRPC and implemented centralized file sharing server.

Work Experience Abroad

IT Manager

Zardozi

September 2012 to 2016

- Served as the technical and communications focal point and liaison between IT and Zardozi regional offices in regards to communications, IT initiatives, and needs assessments.
- Led efforts to improve business application and business technology processes through rigorous data collection and analysis
- Supervised a team of 2 IT Technicians and managed relationships with external vendors and advisors
- Rigorously maintained and forecasted financial budgets to ensure all technical projects were delivered on -time and on budget.

IT Associate

UNAMA

December 2010 to August 2012

- Coordinated site preparation activities for office accommodation.
- Assisted in the acquisition, installation, and maintenance of computer systems involving cisco switches, patch panels/ cords, fiber cables, and linked systems.
- Installed, configured, and resolved networked equipment problems such as digital sender, network printers, plotters, and photocopiers.
- Provided system administration and support on network and Windows servers.

IT Manager

DACAAR

July 2005 to November 2010

- Developed policies, procedure and implementing Technology-related controls.
- Provided support to all devices on the organization's network, including Servers, Desktop workstations, Switches, firewalls, network-attached storage, external storage, HF, VHF, Sat Phones, and other appliances as needed.
- Accomplished financial objectives by forecasting technology requirements; assisted with the preparation of the annual budget; scheduled expenditures; analyzed variances in budget versus actual expenses; initiating corrective action

Education

Master of Business Administration

Roehampton University April 2018

Bachelor in computer Science

Kardan University June 2015

Skills

- Active Directory
- Virtualization/ VMware/ Hyper-V
- · Network Security/Monitoring
- Backup and disaster Recovery
- LAN/VLAN/WAN/VPN/Firewall
- Cisco Routers & Switches
- PowerShell Scripting
- System Installation Configuration & Upgrading
- Windows 10 Imaging MDT
- Training & Mentoring
- Office 365
- PBX/ VOIP
- · Customer support
- DHCP/ DNS
- Microsoft Windows Server
- Windows 10 OS/ Centos

Work style: Conscientiousness — Highly Proficient

December 2020

Tendency to be well-organized, rule-abiding, and hard-working

Full results: Highly Proficient

Technical support — Highly Proficient

May 2021

Performing software, hardware, and network operations.

Full results: <u>Highly Proficient</u>

Basic computer skills — **Expert**

May 2021

Performing basic computer operations and troubleshooting common problems

Full results: Expert

Work style: Professionalism — Proficient

May 2021

Tendency to be accountable, professional, open to feedback, and act with integrity at work

Full results: Proficient

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.